Hi, in this lesson we'll ask the pilot to write unit tests.
Unit tests help ensure our application still works correctly after any change we made.
They automatically check small parts of the code, so every file, every function of the files
that it still works correctly.
And you shouldn't test it manually.
In this lesson, you ask a pilot to generate a unit test for the calculator app, then review
them.
We'll make some changes if needed.
We'll apply fixes if it won't work at the end, but of course it will work, and we'll
confirm the changes.
So we'll focus on testing the main application logic inside of the application component
here.
We'll also focus on testing the details, all the details we have, and we'll ask a pilot
to cover all the cases.
We'll also focus on testing the hook, we have a lot of logic in our hook.
The components, the card components, the display components, the icon button, I noticed
that some of the components we don't use, the card component we don't use, so I simply
I just forget about it, we can just delete this component, not just that the icon won't
cover it with that, so.
I can button the key button, the key part, so we have a logic here.
Okay, I prepared the prompt, so I will use an engine mode, I ask, right, unit test for
the calculator application using the vtest, it's the utl, the writing unit test, similar
to just, I ask cover all main use cases for all components, hooks, utils, and main
up logic, everything I see is important to cover with test, use.spec.ts or the spec.ts,
spec prefix in the file with test, for the name and keep all the tests near the corresponding
file, so we'll help test files close to the, to the other components, hooks, so to be more
easier to update them.
Okay, let's write, let's ask, the power to write the unit test, and then we can,
review it one by one, and see, and evaluate it, if it be satisfied or not.
Let's see, he first analyze the package, the JSON file, and check if we have to install
any libraries, like vtest, or some test details, so what it does, the model wants to
edit sensitive files, back into JSON, do you want to allow this?
Okay, let's allow my video, just add a new library versions, so we'll add a vtest, some
tests in utils, etc, okay, so mark your create the vtest config file, we also need it, it
would like to use the vtest, can you see all the changes here, and now it will create all
the tests one by one, of course, first we need setup, okay, I will just close this files, okay,
and now we have the first test for the format number, so we just test the different cases
like it should handle an empty input, how we handle the menu sign, how we format integer
with 1000 separator, with decimal numbers, and negative one, so we see a really nice, really
edit a lot of test cases, which I like, so just to be sure everything works, okay, let's
check the rest of the tests, we have the test for the display, so we just render the component
and try to find, so with the value, just try to find it render the value, and then we
check that the history is provided, we check the messages exist, I don't know why the message
is displayed, oh yeah, because we just provide a message, so, and should not render empty
history, we have like the cases, the key button, so it will check that it will render
the different buttons, it will click works, and set right applies the correct type of operator
digital control, for the calculate, we have with the addition, the subscriptions, the
multiply, so we see test, the different cases, even with, even with decimals, so I like
it, what else, we have the hook, for the hook we have quite a lot of test cases, so we
have a check that it's limit up to 10 digits, and of the percentage, the total sign, the
AC to clear all the texts, so I like it, okay, what else, the key button, we already
see it, so, we don't write all the tests, we ask, I don't know why, I don't know if we
see the test files, okay, I don't kill, click keep, and stop, so for now I will just test
that all the test works, I will run npm run test, as he suggested, I'll just npm test,
okay, in the same, okay, I think I first need to run npm install just 10,000 new
dependencies, so if this is a case that AI doesn't cover all components you expect, you might
be need to move all the components as a context, we'd like to cover, we just mentioned
them, we had text, and then you will be for sure, he will cover all the components, so
currently, we run the test, and we have 65 tests, let's file it, expect, extend matures,
okay, let's move it, and ask the I to fix it, because I don't like, he wrote the tests
and it doesn't work, so if you need to indentify the error, because when you configure
with this property for your components test, okay, but you didn't configure it properly,
so yeah, now it works, but not all the test works, okay, AI is still fixing all the tests,
what should we fix now, the changes, okay, fix all the tests, demo, them, doesn't work, so
let's see if I don't specify the test, doesn't work, if you fix them, we can copy
the past it, for the case, you won't fix it correctly, because we see one case for the
key button, one case for use calculator, and two cases for application, doesn't work,
so let's see if he wouldn't identify it correctly, because if we say we use the auto model,
I simply use some chip model from pilot, I don't know, and how is it good for writing
the test, but if you'd like to have a good quality use one of the latest model, like, I
know, GPT file for, quote, format, open files of nowadays in the latest model, okay, he's fixing
some of the tests, so yeah, it's nice, okay, I will restart all the tests again, okay, now
the key button doesn't work one test, let's run, I will remove the calculator from here,
fix, in this component, and I will just copy paste what is doesn't work, you also can do
like this, then he will identify faster what doesn't work, and we'll fix it, okay, he sees
the potential issue, okay, now it works, I will stop it, so just if you'd like to cover
more components by unit SEO, just move the files to the context, and you'll just write
the problem, cover all these components by unit SEO, you can just copy paste the prompt, we
type initially, just update it to mode to all hooks, the components, but on the aforementioned
files, and then the Ivo generated for you, so I will keep everything, let's check some
of the tests, for example, for the calculator logic, so we already checked, it makes sense,
not my best time, you for format number, yeah, we see, we have much more cases here, we
do decimals, which is not impossible, in theory, but it might happen, sorry, not impossible
on practice, okay, but it really makes sense, this test really makes sense, okay, you see, sometimes
you can use some deprecated methods, so you also need to be careful, like when you get the
test results and you sometimes need to refactor, so you can ask that this method is deprecated
so this picked to refactor it, okay, if this is fast and it's everything I'd like to show
you, sorry, for the long platform, you see, I didn't hit from across the temp, you may also
face this issue, but now you see my approach, how I fix the test, I try to show you a different
approach, is how I do is to copy paste the terminal message, move files to the context, just
mentioned, fix all the tests, which doesn't work and you might use this approach, okay,
see you in the next lesson.